<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Khaled Nassar</title><link>https://knas.me/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Khaled Nassar</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 22:15:09 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://knas.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Autocompletion for Neovim</title><link>https://knas.me/posts/autocompletion-for-neovim/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 22:15:09 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://knas.me/posts/autocompletion-for-neovim/</guid><description>One of the coolest features that can make you more productive with NeoVim is autocompletion, so we have some plugins to choose between them based on the performance
YouCompleteMe Coc.nvim these plugins are great to use but they are very heavy because of Javascript and Python, so I decided to switch to another solution and the solution is Lua Plugin called nvim-cmp with this plugin you can add an auto-completion to your neovim with minimal performance, all you have to do is download the language server</description></item><item><title>Don't use Python List Everywhere</title><link>https://knas.me/posts/dont-use-python-list-everywhere/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 22:13:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://knas.me/posts/dont-use-python-list-everywhere/</guid><description>the common thing that if you wanna add some items to someplace may thinking to use List, that&amp;rsquo;s great python list has a lot of features that you need like
mutable: you can add/delete what you want from the list ordered: the items have a defined order allowed duplicates: lists can have items with the same value so you will ask me a question if lists have something like that so why should I avoid it then?</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://knas.me/about/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://knas.me/about/</guid><description>EMPTY RIHT NOW</description></item><item><title>the best way to configure your dwm</title><link>https://knas.me/posts/the-best-way-to-configure-your-dwm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://knas.me/posts/the-best-way-to-configure-your-dwm/</guid><description>hello everyone, dwm is the best window manager you can use it&amp;rsquo;s fast and minimalism and this the best thing i love of suckless philosophy , in this post i&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to configure your dwm, we will configure keybinds &amp;amp; color schema &amp;amp; some tasks can help you for make an awesome WM for configure your dwm (or any suckless programs) you need to change somethings in config.h</description></item><item><title>SQL inection on gdclive.nokia.com</title><link>https://knas.me/posts/sql-inection-on-gdclive.nokia.com/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://knas.me/posts/sql-inection-on-gdclive.nokia.com/</guid><description>Hi, this blog about SQL Injection in Nokia.com Allowed me to Dump all database
Full POC : when I&amp;rsquo;m visiting this domain gdclive.nokia.com I&amp;rsquo;ve found something
First: this domain has been used an old version of Joomla CMS
let&amp;rsquo;s scan it using the joomscan tool for dumping all pieces of information about Joomla (plugins, version, etc..)
All results :
Joomla Version: 3.1 Plugins: JCK Editor (6.4.4) searching for JCK Editor in exploit-db.</description></item></channel></rss>